nationet.com 2017-11-13

# KPMG Nunwood - Our Privacy Policy

**KPMG NUNWOOD PRIVACY POLICY    
**  
This website is operated by KPMG Nunwood Consulting Limited, a subsidiary of KPMG Holding Limited, a subsidiary of KPMG LLP ("KPMG", "we" or “us”), a UK limited liability partnership and a member firm of the KPMG network of independent member firms affiliated with KPMG International Cooperative ("KPMG International"), a Swiss entity. KPMG International provides no client services.  
KPMG Nunwood is dedicated to protecting the confidentiality and privacy of information entrusted to it, and complies with the Data Protection Act 1998. Please review this Privacy Statement to learn more about what information we may collect about you through this website and how we use that information. KPMG may also collect personal data in the course of providing professional services (see below for further details).

This policy also covers all client information and research participant data housed at any KPMG Nunwood facility or stored on the KPMG Nunwood network. Anyone at KPMG Nunwood who has access to such information or data must follow this policy.  
The information you give us will be treated with the strictest confidence and in accordance with the Market Research Society Code of Conduct. It will not be passed on to any other person or persons and any personal details you provide will not be used in any sales or marketing activity & no personally identifiable information will be passed onto any third parties unless your consent is given.  
By using this website and submitting information to us you are agreeing to the collection and use of your personal and non-personal information as described in this Privacy Statement and our Cookies Policy.

**THE TYPE OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM USERS**

1\. You do not need to register your personal information in order to use this website. We collect only such personal data as is provided voluntarily by visitors to our website and is necessary in the circumstances. For example, you may provide information such as your name, title, work address and email address in order to register for certain services or to send or receive email to/from us through the site.

**USES OF COLLECTED INFORMATION**

2\. We will use your personal data only for the purpose for which it was collected, unless we obtain your specific consent to other uses, or unless otherwise required or permitted by law or professional standards. For example, if you send us an email message requesting information about KPMG we will use your email address and other information you supply to respond to your request. 

3\. We may share personal data that you submit to us via this website to other member firms in the KPMG network of firms or to suppliers or subcontractors working on our behalf (including transfers across geographical borders worldwide) in accordance with our data protection obligations. 

4\. We do not disclose your personal data to third parties (excluding those identified above) except as required and permitted by applicable law.

5\. We do not sell your personal data or provide it to third parties for their direct marketing use. We may add your personal data to our CRM (Contact Relationship Management) database which we use to develop our relationship with current and prospective contacts.

 **RESEARCH PARTICIPANT INFORMATION  
**  
6\. All responses to our research are completely confidential. We collect data in our studies for research purposes only, and our use of that information will be limited to that purpose. Research participant answers will not be used by any entity as an aid for sales.

7\. Calls made for the purpose of research are exempt from TPS (Telephone Preference Service) which only applies to sales and marketing calls. Therefore we are entitled to call ex-directory numbers, however, we will not release your personal information to any third party without your consent.

8\. Research participation is voluntary and sample members always have the opportunity to decline involvement or to ‘opt out’ of the research after agreeing to participate. We do not collect personal information without research participant consent.

9\. We do not rent, sell or give personal information to any third party for the purpose of directly marketing any products or services. In some cases we may need to share personal information with third parties that provide research services in support of the research project. Any third party that receives personal information is obligated to follow all of the same privacy protection regulations as followed by KPMG Nunwood.

10\. At their request, we give research participants access to the personal information we have collected about them. We correct any information that is inaccurate or incomplete, change their consent status, or have their personal information deleted.

 **CHILDREN  
**  
11\. We do not contact children under the age of 18 without consent from a parent or guardian.

**COMPLIANCE**

12\. The information you give us will be treated with the strictest confidence and in accordance with the Market Research Society Code of Conduct. It will not be passed on to any other person or persons and any personal details you provide will not be used in any sales or marketing activity & no personally identifiable information will be passed onto any third parties unless your consent is given.

 **COOKIES**

13\. Our website uses cookies. Read about how we use Cookies.

**DATA SECURITY AND STORAGE  
**  
14\. KPMG Nunwood has appropriate technical and organisational security policies and procedures in place to protect personal data and information from loss, misuse, alteration, or destruction.

15\. Additionally, we aim to ensure that access to your personal data is limited to those who need to access it. Those individuals who have access to the data are required to maintain the confidentiality of such information.

16\. Please be aware that the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data which is transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

17\. We use reasonable efforts to retain personal data collected from you only for so long as we need such data in accordance with the purpose for which it was collected or until we are requested to delete it (if earlier).

**ACCESS TO COLLECTED INFORMATION  
**  
18\. You have the right to request a copy of personal data (as defined in the Data Protection Act 1998) that we keep about you, and to have any inaccurate information about you corrected. If you wish to make such a request or you are concerned that any of the information we possess about you is incorrect, please contact us at info@kpmg-nunwood.co.uk.

 **UNSUBSCRIBE**

19\. If you wish to unsubscribe from any KPMG Nunwood mailing list or registration, we will provide instructions on the appropriate web page or communication or please contact us at info@kpmg-nunwood.co.uk.

**LINKS TO OTHER SITES  
**  
20\. KPMG Nunwood web sites may contain links to other sites, including sites maintained by other KPMG member firms that are governed by other privacy statements that may differ in content to this Privacy Statement. Please review the privacy policy of each web site you visit before submitting any personal information to it. Whilst we try to link only to sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the content, security, or privacy practices employed by other sites.

**PROVISION OF PROFESSIONAL SERVICES  
**  
21\. KPMG Nunwood will also often receive personal information in the course of providing professional services – ordinarily when we provide services to private individuals, employers, businesses with personal customers, and public sector clients with constituents. Our engagement letter and terms of business govern our relationship with clients, including what we may do with personal data that is provided to us. KPMG Nunwood provides many different types of services and its role may not always be visible to the individuals who are data subjects.

22\. Accordingly, if you have a privacy query or concern you should first contact your employer or the relevant organisation with whom you have a relationship (e.g. your bank). They will be in the best position to advise you.

23\. More generally, KPMG Nunwood complies with its obligations under the Data Protection Act 1998, and applicable regulatory guidance which relates to our handling of personal data (for example, as published by our principal regulators, the Institute of Chartered Accountants in England and Wales) and the Market Research Society. Regulatory information about KPMG can be found here.

**CHANGES TO THIS POLICY  
**  
24\. KPMG Nunwood keeps this Privacy Statement under regular review and may modify or amend it from time to time at our discretion. If we make changes, we will record the date of amendment or modification in the Privacy Statement. The revised Privacy Statement will apply to you and your information from that date. We would encourage you to review this Privacy Statement periodically to check if there are any changes in how we are treating your personal data. This Privacy Statement was last updated in October 2015.

**CONTACTING US  
**  
25\. If you have questions, comments or complaints about our handling or protection of your personal data, please contact us at [info@kpmg-nunwood.co.uk](mailto:info@kpmg-nunwood.co.uk "Contact us").
